KAYITARE Cynthia

Kigali - Kicukiro, Phone Number: +250 785627690

Email: kacynthian@gmail.com Portfolio: https://kayitares.github.io/my-brand

Linkedin:https://www.linkedin.com/in/KAYITARES

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a hard-working, integral person and full stack developer with an ambition to become a senior developer. I have a bachelor's degree in Information Technology(IT) and am extremely knowledgeable with experience in web application development. I am a strongly reliable person and highly efficient in everything I undertake.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Assistant Software Engineering Instructor

SheCanCODE March 2022- Now

- Teaching HTML,CSS, JAVASCRIPT,REACT JS
- Technical assistance on the Node Js
- Technical assistance on the student project
- Product owner of Igire Rwanda Organization Website where I lead Igire Rwanda Interns to built the Igire Rwanda Organization Web.
- Participated in interviews, assessments and recruiting SheCanCODE cohort 6 students.
- Develop Academy Women Entrepreneurs Rwanda website.

Technical Mentor June 2019- June 2021

KLAB

- Creating lesson plans to be delivered to students
- Teaching HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Github, Javascript, and Python to students (Gihembe Refugees & KLAB Students)
- Technical assistance on the project created for students

Technical Mentor

August 2021-December 2021

WIA Training

- Creating lessons plans to be delivered to students
- Teaching HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and assistance in delivering PHP courses to students
- Technical assistance on project creation and hosting for students

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

SHE-CAN-CODE

November 2021-February 2022

Coursework: Node js, React JS, Mongo DB and web deployment

University of Michigan

November 2021

Coursework: Advanced styling with responsive design

Johns Hopkins University

October 2021

Coursework: HTML, CSS, and Javascript for Web Developers

Google IT Specialist

December 2020 - March 2021

November October 2018-May 2019

Coursework: Technical Support Fundamentals, The Bits and Bytes of Computer Networking, Operating System, System Administration, and IT Infrastructure Services, IT security

Moringa School N Coursework: Software Engineer: Full Stack Specialization

University of Kigali (UOK)

September 2014-July2018

Bachelor's degree in Information Technology (Hons)

Coursework: Java Programming, Server and System Administration, Database Management System, Internet Programming, and Web design

HIGHLIGHTED SOFTWARE APPLICATION

LOST & FOUND January-February 2022

URL:https://lost-found-doc.netlify.app/

Lost & found is a website that helps to find lost documents, and was created by a group of 4 people with the role of a front-end developer and assisting in the back-end.

- Accept to create an account.
- Accept to upload a lost or a found document.
- Able to notify both users lost and user found if the lost document has been found.
- Implemented in React JS for frontend, Node JS for backend, and MongoDB for the database

Tel:+250 788 737 287

ACADEMY WOMAN ENTREPRENEURS

URL:https://awe-rwanda.netlify.app/

The website shows what the AWE is doing. I am still working on it.

• Created using Javascript Programming Language with React Js, CSS, Material UI.

PERSONAL SKILLS

Jean Jacques

Adaptability	An	nbitious	Prob	lem solver	Loyalty	Quick learner	
TECHNICAL	SKILLS	S					
HTML	CSS	В	ootstrap	Django	PostgreSQL	Node JS	
React JS	Linux	Py	thon	Github	JavaScript	Command Line	
UI/UX Design	Sass	Fl	ask	Angular JS	Networking	SQL	
SPOKEN LAN	NGUAG	ES					
French (Intermediate)		English (Advanced)		Kiswahili (elementary proficiency)	(exp	Kinyarwanda (expert)	
REFERENCE	S						
Cynthia Kasambuli		Moringa School		Tel: +254 798742352			
Aphrodice Mutangana		C.E.O Digital Africa		Tel: +250 783 011 878			
Yeetah Kamikazi			KLAB Manager		Tel: +250 782 742 723		

C.E.O SheCanCODE